Girona, Spain

🔾 wilberquito | in wilberquito | 🌴 wilberquito.github.io | 🗗 typingwil@gmail.com | 🗖 (+34) 698-40-53-59

"The best way to predict the future is to create it."

About Me

With more than three years of experience in IT solutions, I began my career as a Software Developer. However, I quickly transitioned to datadriven solutions, focusing on Machine Learning and statistical methods. I am also passionate about developing personal projects, including short posts, video game development, and engaging in physical sports whenever possible.

Education

University of Girona GIRONA, SPAIN

MSc. in Data Science 🗞

Sep. 2023

· Studies focused on advanced skills in analyzing and deriving insights from data using statistical and machine learning methods.

University of Girona GIRONA, SPAIN

BEng. in Computer Science ®

Jun. 2022

· I take pride in my accomplishment of attaining excellence in the final degree project, which entailed the creation of an open-source video game.

Work Experience

Citibeats BARCELONA, SPAIN

Data Scientist Sep. 2023 - Mar. 2024

- · Conducted topic modeling pipelines, anomaly detection events with explainability to comprehend phenomena within time series, and clustering solutions for the identification of relevant groups.
- · Created private Python libraries, web-hook services, and deployed trained models in private registers.
- · Provided technical support for previous company projects, i.e., fixing bugs, adding features, and refitting models.
- · Researched and implemented fast experiments, documenting the process for reproducibility and its results.
- I was in charge of defining the working framework in the Data Science team, i.e., defining the tools for research, development and deployment.

University of Girona GIRONA, SPAIN

Associate Assistant Professor

Feb. 2023 - Aug. 2023

· My responsibilities included overseeing lab sessions in order to instruct students in functional and logic programming, correct lab projects, and supervise exams.

Accenture SL GIRONA, SPAIN

Computer Vision Research

Dec. 2022 - Aug. 2023

 Created and open source Computer-Aided Diagnosis platform for detecting Melanoma using Convolutional Neural Networks.

Nexus Geographics GIRONA, SPAIN

Data Engineer

Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022

- · Significantly contributed to the development of a concurrent framework designed to capture, map, and store data from diverse sources.
- · Created and manteined API micro-services to injest and serve data. Ensuring data consistency across multiple databases.
- · Designed and developed interactive web applications to visualize on-demand and streaming data.
- · Provided training to new team members on the primary technologies utilized in the projects and offered problem-solving support.

NexTReT Girona, Spain

Software Engineer Abr. 2020 - Sep. 2021

- Designed and developed a wide range of Restful APIs.
- Created interactive web applications for the healthcare sector, taking responsibility for building modules including authentication, hospital bed administration, external hospital services, and more.

Tech Skills

Programming Languages Python, R, Haskell, Scala, Java, JS, C++, and more

ML & Data Tools PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, Hugging Face, Pandas, SQL, Kafka, and more

MLOps / DevOps MLFlow, W&B, Docker, GitHub Actions, and Git

Frameworks FastAPI, Flask, Spring Boot, Svelte, Angular, and more **Workflow** Jupyter Notebook, Neovim, Linux, GitHub and GitLab

Cloud AWS and Google Colab

Other Skills of Interest

Languages English (C1), Spanish (Native), Catalan (Bilingual)

Driver's License B

Certificates

2023 Prevention & Emergency Management, Co-funded by the Erasmus+ Programme of the European Union

2022 Spark and Python for Big Data with PySpark, Udemy

2022 Advanced Machine Learning, Kaggle

2022 Advanced SQL, Kaggle

2021 Advanced Functional Programming (FP), University of Helsinki

References_

PROF. DR. MATEU VILLARET
PROFESSOR AT UNIVERSITY OF GIRONA
MATEU.VILLARET@UDG.EDU

PROF. DR. GUSTAVO PATOW PROFESSOR AT UNIVERSITY OF GIRONA GUSTAVO.PATOW@UDG.EDU

QUIM DALMAU **S**TECH LEAD AT CITIBEATS
JDALMAUT@GMAIL.COM